

PROFILE

Seasoned and independent Front-End Developer with more than 2 years of experience in blending the art of design with skill of programming using HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, TypeScript with TDD unit testing: plus, modem libraries and frameworks such as ReactJS, NextJS as well as NodeJS to building and maintaining responsive websites with maintaining design pattern principles such as SOLID in the recruiting industry.

CONTACT

PHONE: 01994688976

LINKEDIN:

linkedin.com/in/habibur-rahman-06166b1b6

EMAIL:

mdhabiburrb@gmail.com

PORTFOLIO:

https://hr-bappy.github.io/Portfolio/

GITHUB:

https://github.com/HR-Bappy

ACTIVITIES AND INTERESTS

- Competitive programming
- Travelling
- · Solving problem (math and
- IQ) Most importantly interested in learning more and new thing

HABIBUR RAHMAN

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front-End Engineer at SWAP

December 2022 to Present Build SWAP marketplace using NextJs.

Front-End Developer WebX Global Ltd.

May 2022 to November 2022

→ Develop CMS merchant panel with reactJS and landing page using nextJs (webx.xyz)

Front-End Developer

Shafa Care

March 2021 to February 2022

- → Designed telemedicine website and ShafaDev static website using NextJS.
- → Build web-based video calling system using agora.io with NextJS.
- → Developed ShafaCare admin dashboard using ReactJS and REST API

Jr. Front-End Developer + Intern

Halcyon

September 2020 to March 2021

- → Designed 2 websites using ReactJs.
- \rightarrow Utilized HTML, CSS, JavaScript to create 100+ responsive landing pages for both company and client using HTML CSS and JS according to PSD file.
- \rightarrow Responsible for maintaining website and deploy on the server.

EDUCATION

B. Sc. In CSE

International University of Business Agriculture and Technology 2017 to 2020 With CGPA: 3.73 out of 4

KEY SKILLS AND CHARACTERISTICS

Language:

C++ JAVA HTML CSS SASS JavaScript Typescript

Libraries:

ReactJs React-Redux NextJs NodeJs

CI/CD:

Git

Project Management:

Trello, Jira

ACADAMIC PROJECT

- School Management System C, C++
- Ride Boat on a River OpenGL, C++
- Procurement Management System Java, JavaFX, MySQL
- University Attendance System Java, JavaFX, MySQL
- School Management System Java, JavaFX, MySQL
- Weather App
 HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Portfolio HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- FootWear ReactJS
- Online Shopping and Trail ReactJS, MySOL
- Real Time Video and Text Chat App Socket.io, NodeJS

ACHIEVEMENTS

Problem Solving

- → Solved more than 1000 problems in different online judge
- → Participate different Math IQ test

Competitive Programming

- ightarrow Attended 2 times NCPC in 2018 and 2020 Hosted by IUBAT and SUST
- → Participate more than 12 National and Inter University Programming Contest and got Certificate
- → Attend Google Hash Code Programming Contest in 2020

Course and Certificate →

Completed many online and offline courses and got certificate

VOLUNTEERING

- → Mentor of intermediate and beginner session of IUBAT Programming club
- → Based on competitive programming arranged different seminar such as: weekly programming session, monthly programming contest.
- → Help students for academic courses and projects

REFERENCES

Dr. Utpal Kanti Das

Professor& Chairman, Department of CSE (IUBAT)

Email: ukd@iubat.edu

Mohammad Sajid Shahria

Lecturer, Department of CSE (IUBAT)

Email: sajid@iubat.edu

SIGNATURE



Habibur Rahman